BRADLEY LUND

• DETAILS •

South Africa +27767899191 bradjlund@gmail.com

LINKS

<u>LinkedIn</u>

Github

Portfolio Website

o SKILLS o

React

Next.js

JavaScript

Express.js

Node.js

Git

CSS

HTML

SQL

MongoDB

SQL Server Management Studio SQL Server Reporting Service

D3.js

LANGUAGES

English

Spanish

• HOBBIES •

Multiple South African champion in Orienteering

Competed for South Africa at the World Orienteering Championships in 2019 in Norway

Ultra-Marathon runner

Ukulele

PROFILE

Hard-working, quick learning Individual with a strong drive to constantly develop myself and enhance my abilities.

An individual with strong interpersonal and communication skills who enjoys working on teams.

Gaining a degree in Actuarial Science has given me a firm base and understanding of risk, mathematics, statistics, and probability and taught me how these complex subjects interlink. This background has allowed me to merge these concepts with my development and coding experience, and enhance my problem-solving ability using both of these skill sets.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Business Analyst at Signature Business Solutions - Discovery Invest, Johannesburg September 2020 — Present

Automating the reconciliation process at VatGlobal, I am now working on automating solutions at Discovery Invest.

The solutions are implemented through writing efficient stored procedures and matching algorithms where complex logic is required. We use SQL Server Management Studio and SQL Server Reporting Services daily to accomplish business needs.

Thought up and implemented automated solutions which improved the automatic reconciliation rate by 50% working for Discovery Invest.

Won an employee recognition award for outstanding performance in 2021,

Trained up new employees in SQL, SSMS and SQL Server Management Studios. The junior went from minimal experience in writing SQL to being able to build complicated reports with advanced query logic.

Received a 5/5 rating "Doing Bosses Job" at the biannual performance review

English Teaching Assistant at IES Margarita Salas, Madrid

September 2018 — July 2020

Prepared and taught lessons for Spanish children between 5 and 18 years old covering a wide variety of topics including gender equality and stereotypes to fun Christmas activities for the youngsters.

Collaborated with other teachers from around the world to create interesting lesson content educating Spanish children about different cultures.

Mathematics and Sciences Tutor at Master Maths, Johannesburg

March 2018 — July 2018

OTHER EXPERIENCE

Passport Pals, Johannesburg

August 2020

Built a script using puppeteer that scraped Wikipedia data on visa requirements for all countries. Used MongoDB as the database, Express, and Node.js for the back-end. Any two people from two different countries can use the website to see where they can travel to together visa-free.

EDUCATION

Full Stack Web Developer Bootcamp, HyperionDev, Johannesburg

October 2021

I learned how to successfully build and deploy dynamic web applications using modern technologies. The focus was on the MERN exposing me to the JavaScript development environment.

Bachelor of Science in Actuarial and Financial Mathematics, University of Pretoria, Pretoria

November 2017

The core subjects in my degree were Mathematics and Mathematical Statistics. In Mathematical Statistics we used SAS to do hypothesis testing and build statistical models.

Started and ran the Tuks Orienteering Club. Hosting a number of Gauteng Orienteering league events and training sessions bi-weekly.

Fourways High School, Johannesburg

2007 - 2011

Matriculated with 5 distinctions for the subjects: Mathematics (90%), Information Technology (87%), Physical Science, Biology, and Life Orientation.

Through vote by my peers and teachers, I was elected as Deputy Head Boy and Head of Sports and Culture. My responsibilities included organizing inter-house sports events and orientation week for the grade eights.

Selected to play hockey for the Southern Gauteng under 18 hockey team at an inter-provincial tournament.

❖

COURSES

Javascript Algorithms and Data Structures, freeCodeCamp

APIs and Microservices, freeCodeCamp

MTA: Database Fundamentals (100%), Microsoft

Completed all SQL problems, HackerRank

Data Visualization with D3, freeCodeCamp